# JOSEPH PERCIVAL

Tel: 07709718757 Linked In: www.linkedin.com/in/joseph-percival/ email: joseph.m.percival@gmail.com

# PROFESSIONAL PROFILE

Accomplished UX Designer with 4+ Years of experience specialising in designing intuitive, user-focused web pages and mobile apps across a variety of industries, resulting in successful sales and traffic increases. Able to combine both creativity and usability to create world class websites and mobile apps for the retail and technology industries. Proven experience in optimising user satisfaction and engagement, resulting in increased traffic and company sales. Commercially focused on business and user needs with a consistent record of accomplishment in design/development projects from conception to market launch.

# **SKILLS & ABILITIES**

1st Class BSc (Hons) degree in UX Design & Web Development (Edge Hill University 2019) · UX Research · UX Design · UI Design · UX Testing · Wireframing · Rapid Prototyping · Designing to WCAG Accessibility standards · Data Visualization · User Stories · Customer Satisfaction · Information Architecture · HTML5 · CSS3 · Prototyping · Adobe XD · Figma · Leadership · Communication

# **EXPERIENCE**

# December 2021 - Present

# Senior UX Designer & Senior UI Designer - Synaliogik Solutions, Tewkesbury, England - Full Time - Remote

#### Outline

The only designer at a successful data aggregation and data supplier organisation. Responsible for creating intuitive user focused design updates on the current platform, redesigning the new User Interface to meet modern Web standards with the goal to increase online sales and improved User Experience.

- Designed and developed the organisations E-Commerce marketing strategy prototype for their products.
- Redesigned the new UI for their platform used by UK Governments, Councils, Police and Special Crimes Departments.
- Lead the Design Authority on strategy, planning and design for new products with the Product Manager and Development Manager.
- Involved with the organisation's Senior meetings regarding processes in Design, Planning and Development.
- Created and enforced content and interaction standards, guidance, and style patterns for the organisation.
- Articulate the value of User Experience, content, and interaction design, coaching senior leaders
  across the organisation to understand the connection between excellent content and excellent
  service. Create innovative digital solutions with a streamlined, user focused approach.
- · Leading the end-to-end design process, focused on User Interaction, to maximise user workflow.
- Produced Data Driven Designs concluded from triangulated data from Qualitative and Quantifiable data
- Produced Designs that are researched and compliant to modern standards of Typography, layout, color, grid systems, and advanced design principles.
- Advocated the importance of Accessibility and being compliant to WCAG AA standard as a minimum, from design to development release.
- Prototyped utilising Design techniques and User Research, with Sketches and in Adobe XD.
   Ensuring WCAG, HTML5 and CSS3 standards are followed and are achievable for developers.
- Engaged the wider team (C level, developers, and marketing employees) in the user-centric design process.
- Instigated projects, prioritise workload and planning.
- Supplied support to all developers at every Seniority level to meet design specifications.
- Supplied a positive working environment that considers the needs of a diverse team.

#### January 2021 -

### UX Designer and Front-End Developer Contractor - Freelance - Hybrid

Dec 2021

Outline

UX Consultant for various companies in the Northwest and significantly increased sales for each company after recommendations and redesigns were developed.

- Analysed clients' websites through applications utilising Google Analytics metrics and scoped failing issues.
- Investigated user behavior and market demographics.
- · Created storyboards using Adobe XD.
- Analyzed and synthesized qualitative and quantitative data to distill meaningful findings to improve the information architecture design process.
- Conducted user research using a wide variety of qualitative and quantitative research methods, inperson and remote.
- Conducted and user evaluated a range of design concepts and prototypes.
- · Triangulated the Qualitative and Quantitative data from the User Research Testing.
- Made recommendations to improve site functionality, accessibility, marketing, footfall.
- Lead stakeholder meetings on planning project, budgets and facilitated User Testing.
- Redesigned clients E-Commerce components using advanced marketing techniques to upsell and subtly promote items.
- Designed using Adobe Creative Suite.
- Prototyped and User Tested in Semantic HTML5 and CSS3.

#### May 2020 - Jan 2021

### Software Developer - The Hut Group, Manchester - Full Time - Remote

### Outline

Designed and Developed E-Commerce websites for Calvin Klein, L'oreal, Coca-Cola, Nike, and Adidas.

- Collaborated with cross-functional team of designers, product management, and copywriters solving concepts to solutions that are effective, authentic, and innovative.
- Collaborated with UX team members, Development teams, Product Owners, Users, and other stakeholders as part of an agile software development process.
- Utilised my UX knowledge and skills during the coding sessions.
- Efficient in using the company's Content Management System and Design Tools.
- Use markup languages such as HTML5 and CSS3 to create user-friendly web pages.
- · Maintain and improve website.
- · Optimize applications for maximum speed.
- Collaborate with back-end developers and web designers to improve usability.
- · Write functional requirement documents and guides.
- · Create quality mockups and prototypes.
- Ensure high quality graphic standards and brand consistency by following the design specifications.
- Stay up to date on emerging technologies.
- Involved with git repo pull request sign offs and critique processes.

# Feb 2020 - May 2020

# Web Designer - Freelance - Hybrid

#### Outline

Designed and provided scalable solutions for several small businesses and charities in the Northwest of England.

- Lead stakeholder meetings on planning project, budgets and facilitated User Testing.
- Created Project Planning and Time Management with realistic milestones, phases of the design and development process.
- Research and Design User Stories from the Business and User Requirement Analysis.
- Create User Centric Wireframes, test with the client then move onto high fidelity prototypes in Adobe XD.
- Test ethically throughout the design and development stages with the client.
- Use markup languages such as HTML5 and CSS3 to create user-friendly web pages.

- · Maintain and improve website.
- Optimize applications for maximum speed.
- Revise and Research suitable frameworks (if needed) for individual projects.
- Write functional requirement documents and guides for future developers.

## Graduate UX and Front-End Developer - Blinx Solutions Ltd - Full-time

#### July 2019 - Jan 2020

#### <u>Outline</u>

Designed and provided scalable solutions for data aggregation organisations in the medical and energy services.

- · Reviewed design mock-ups and providing feedback to designers on the usability of the product.
- Creating prototypes of new features that need to be built, using HTML5 and CSS3.
- Writing code based on designs created by designers.
- · Creating cross browser compatible websites that work well on mobile devices.
- Working with back-end developers to ensure that data is stored correctly in databases.
- Managing projects and tasks for multiple clients simultaneously.
- Testing new features for bugs or defects to ensure that they work properly.
- Debugging code using debugging tools such as Firebug or Chrome inspector.

# **EDUCATION**

Sept 2016 – July 2019	BSc (Hons) Computer Science, majoring in Web Design and Web Development – First Class Certification, Ormskirk, Lancashire (UK), <i>Edge Hill University</i> .
Sept 2016 – Dec 2016	Level 5 - HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript Fundamentals, Ormskirk, Lancashire (UK), Edge Hill University.
Sept 2014 – Dec 2016	Level 3 - ITQ, St. Helens, Merseyside, St. Helens College.
Sept 2014 – Dec 2016	Level 2 - ITQ, St. Helens, Merseyside, St. Helens College.

# **PERSONAL INTERESTS**

I enjoy exercising, going to the Gym, Swimming, the team involvement in playing Football and Rugby and I enjoy Cycling. I enjoy spending time and having fun with my two children, I also enjoy learning and teaching Guitar too. I like to Design and code in my spare time, love researching modern technologies, trying them out and integrating them into my personal projects.